♪〜
〜♪
（モネヴ･ザ･ゲイル）
ハア ハア ハア…
ハア ハア…
Aren't you going to shoot me?
う… 撃たないのか？
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
命令したやつは どこにいる？
Where is your boss?
（モネヴ）ハア ハア ハア…
か… 買われたのさ 俺は
I was bought...
親だと思っていた男も
ただのエージェントだったらしい
The man I thought was my father
must have been an agent.
l-I don't know anything else.
そ… それ以上のことは
何も知らねえ
（モネヴ）ああ…
とんだ甘ちゃんだな
You're way too trusting.
I could shoot you in the back.
俺が後ろから撃ったら
どうするんだ？
こっちのトリガーにも
指が掛かっているのさ
I also have my finger
on the trigger.
（モネヴの震える声）
Mr. Vash...
（メリル･ストライフ）
ヴァッシュさん…
（タイプライターを打つ音）
Routine report,
date: July 20th...
（メリル）
７月20日(はつか)付け 定例報告書
モネヴという男が
起こした事件から２日目
... two days after the incident
caused by a man named Monev.
町の緊張は
いまだ解けていません
Tension still runs
high in the city.
今回 私は
改めて思い知らされました
This incident made me realize
something all over again.
Contact with the real Vash the Stampede
makes me forget his reputation...
ふだん彼と接していると—
どんどん薄れていく
認識なのですが…
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードが—
... the reason he's called
'The Humanoid Typhoon. '
“ヒューマノイド･タイフーン”と
呼ばれるゆえん
なぜ彼のもとには—
Why is it that so much trouble
falls into this man's lap?
こうも大きなトラブルが
数多く転がり込むのでしょうか
今から４か月前—
Four months ago, we, Meryl Stryfe
and Milly Thompson, employees...
ディセムバに本社を構える—
... of the Bernardelli Insurance
Society main office in December...
ベルナルデリ保険協会の
社員である—
メリル･ストライフと
メリィ･トンプソンは—
... were handed our orders.
上司からの辞令を受けました
目的は Ｇ級器物破損容疑で—
Our objective was to come in
contact with Vash the Stampede...
... a man wanted for
$ $60,000,000,000...
600億ダブドルの
賞金を懸けられている—
... under suspicion of
class-G property damage.
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードと
接触すること
そして 彼に随行し—
We were then to keep any
trouble around him in check...
起こりうるトラブルの抑制
および—
... as well as bring a quick resolution
to trouble that had already started.
発生したトラブルを
早期に解決することでした
（バーのマスター）
ヴァッシュって？ 何だ あんたら
Vash? Who are you two?
カワイイ顔して—
Are you innocent-looking things
after the $ $60,000,000,000 reward?
600億ダブドルの賞金首
狙ってんのかい？
Not at all.
違いますわ
We're here on business.
（メリィ･トンプソン）
私たち お仕事で来たんです
仕事…
Business?
まあ 俺は
直接 見たわけじゃねえが—
Well, I didn't see him myself...
...but they say he
left town before dawn.
明け方ごろに町から
いなくなったらしい
東のほうに向かったって話だ
They say he went east.
Can you tell us
what he looks like?
どんな人物か分かります？
うん？ ああ…
He stands about 12 feel tall
and wields a huge weapon.
身の丈12フィールぐらいでー
巨大な武器を振り回すらしい
（客たち）ひいっ！
（バーのマスター）それと—
And he's supposed
to have a Mohawk.
モヒカン刈りの男って聞いたな
手下の数も かなりいて—
He has tons of henchmen...
女癖は最低を通り越して
最悪だそうだ
...and is the worst kind
of womanizer out there.
先輩
Ma'am!
巨大な武器を持つ
モヒカン刈りの男
A man with a huge
weapon and a Mohawk.
That's him all right!
間違いありませんわ
（タイプライターを打つ音）
Having obtained information of
someone matching Vash's description...
（メリル）
ヴァッシュと思わしき人物の
情報を知った私たちは—
... we finally achieved contact
with him after 3 months.
３か月目にして
ついに 彼との接触を果たしました
（デカルト）何だ 貴様ら
What do you want?
は… 初めてお目に
かっ かかります
P-Pleased to m-meet you!
I'm Meryl Stryfe from
the Bernardelli Insurance Society.
わ… 私は
ベルナルデリ保険協会の—
メリル･ストライフと申します
I'm Milly Thompson!
ミリィ･トンプソンです
Please accept this
token of good will!
こ… これ
つまらない物ですけど
Smooth, ma'am!
ナイスです 先輩！
何しに来た？
こいつの仲間か？
What're you doing here?
You with him?
（ヴァッシュ）エヘッ
It was him.
He is Vash the Stampede!
（メリル）彼です
彼が ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
なのです
えらく事実と違いますねえ
That's way different
from how it happened.
A few lies are acceptable
in the name of expedience.
多少のウソは方便ですわよ
Do you want a promotion, Milly?
ミリィは
昇進したくありませんの？
ヘッ？ ハッ ハハハハ　ハア…
（メリル）
確かに一目 見ただけでは—
At first glance,
I couldn't tell it was him.
彼が本物であるとは
分かりませんでした
なぜなら—
This was because he
didn't act anything like...
彼は 伝説のガンマンと
うわさされる人物像とは—
... the legendary gunman
he was made out to be.
まるで違う行動を
取っていたからです
Stop it!!
やめてよ
Just a drink, bro!
（フランク･マーロン）
おごってくれよー 兄貴！
捨てないでくれよー
Don't forsake me!!
（ヴァッシュ）放して 放して
わあー 分かったから放して
Let go! Let go!
All right, all right! Just let go!
（メリル）無視しますわよ 無視！
- Ignore him.
All right, all right! Just let go!
Insurance girls!
（ヴァッシュ）
あっ！ 保険屋さーん
- Ma'am...
- What, you're going?!
（ミリィ）先輩！
（ヴァッシュ）
あっ 行っちゃうのお？
How could you be so cold?!
つれないぞ 君たち！
Don't be so cold,
little brother!
つれねえな 兄弟
（マーロン）ううっ！
（ヴァッシュ）ああ…
He was exasperatingly hopeless,
and not only that...
（メリル）彼は果てしなく
どうしようもない男で—
- HELP!!
He was exasperatingly hopeless,
and not only that...
さらに…
（マリアンヌ）ウフッ
（メリル）ん？
（ヴァッシュのにやけた声）
（メリル）うわっ
... his incorrigible DonJuanism
made him an exasperating idiot.
（メリル）彼は筋金入りの好色で
果てしないバカ者でした
You can count on me, Mr. Cliff.
任せておいてください
クリフさん
（メリル）ぐっ
I don't let anyone
in my sights get away...
（ヴァッシュ）
僕は狙った獲物を逃がさないし
...and my bullets
never miss their mark.
撃った弾(たま)を外したこともない
特に 美しい女性のハートはね
Especially if it's the heart
of a beautiful lady.
バーン！
Bang!
うおー！
（ヴァッシュ）ん？
（ミリィ）先輩！
Ma'am!
だあーっ
お… 思い出しただけでも
心臓が破裂しそうになりますわ
Just remembering it
makes my heart burst a vessel.
Mr. Vash was so
funny back then!
あのころのヴァッシュさん
おかしかったですよね
He wasn't funny,
he was downright weird!
“おかしかった”じゃなくて
おかしいんですわよ
Not even a genius could
tell that goofball was him!
あんなの見て 誰が
本物だと分かるっていうんですの？
マジで
But I thought it
was him from the start.
でも 私
最初からそうだと思ってましたよ
先輩が
信じてなかったんじゃないですかあ
You're the one who
refused to believe it.
Have you finished
writing those papers?
書類は書き終わったのかしら？
Right, ma'am!
I'll keep at it!
はい　頑張ります！
（メリル）うん！
He tried to fool us with his perfect
portrayal of a good-for-nothing...
（メリル）
見事な ろくでなしぶりを披露し
私たちを翻弄した彼でしたが—
... but it was clear to me that
was merely his characteristic pose.
それは 彼特有の
ポーズであることは明白でした
I could tell as I watched him resolve
every incident he was involved in.
関わった事件を次々に解決していく
彼の姿を見ていれば分かります
Suicide?
（ヴァッシュ）自殺？
I disapprove of suicide
more than anything.
それは俺が一番嫌いな行為だ
（デカルト）ふん
Then the boomerang you get.
なら ブーメランの露だな
うーん
いやあああーっ！
はっ！
（ヴァッシュ）ふん！
What?!
（デカルト）なに？
（デカルト）うーん…
（ヴァッシュ）ふっ！
（ヴァッシュ）てへっ
It's only fun until
someone gets hurt!
こんな危ない物(もん)
使っちゃダメだよお
（リールが巻かれる音）
てめえ！
You!!
ああああっ
（体が締まる音）
（手下たち）頭(かしら)！
Boss!
うわあ！
あっ…
（銃声）
あっ
（メリルとミリィ）あっ！
（クリフ）はっ
わっ　こわー！
YEEK!
クッソー！
Damn!
だあっ　おっ
えっ　はっ　わっ
おっ　危ない
Hey!
はっ　ほっ　危ない
Stop that!
はあーっ！
You're a bad shot.
ヘタっぴなの
（クリフ）おわっ
なっ な… 何なんだ？ 貴様
W-Who the hell are you?!
あんたに雇われた
すご腕の用心棒さ
I'm your ace bodyguard.
（銃声）
（悪党のリーダー）
なんだ てめえは
What are you supposed
to be, a hero cowboy?!
ヒーロー気取りのカウボーイか？
Nah, I'm not that great.
そんな 偉そうなもんじゃ
ありませんよ
（タイヤの空気が抜ける音）
Oh, no. You have a flat tire!
あっ 大変だ
パンクしましたよ
You can't get away in this.
これじゃ 逃げられませんねえ
（悪党の手下ＡとＢ）どあー
（悪党のリーダー）
くっ… この野郎！
You little...
（発砲音）
（ヴァッシュ）だだだだ…
Ow, ow, ow!
（ヴァッシュ）ああ…
（悪党の手下Ｃ）ヘヘヘヘッ
おっ！ ぐっ この
Son of a...
放せ この野郎…
Let go, you...
アイタタタ…
He's unbelievable!
（悪党の手下Ｂ）なんて野郎だ
Do you know what'll
happen if you do that?!
（悪党の手下Ａ）
てめえ—
そんなことして
どうなるか分かってんだろうな
ここにいるお方は—
This gent here is the much-feared
Humanoid Typhoon...
ヒューマノイド･タイフーンと
恐れられている—
...Vash the Stampede!
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
なんだぜ！
おかしいな
That's funny...
Pardon me.
（悪党の手下Ｄ）ああー！
（ヴァッシュ）ごめん
もっといい男って
聞いてたんだけどなあ
I heard he was
more handsome.
そ… それじゃ俺が
ヴァッシュじゃねえってのか！
Are you implyin' I'm not Vash?!
試してみようか？
Want to find out?
He was a superb gunman
just as the rumors claimed...
（メリル）
彼は うわさどおりのすご腕で
数々の事件を—
... and every incident
he was in was swiftly...
事件を…
... was swiftly...
He did it so haphazardly, how could
I think it was anything but dumb luck?!
あんな
いいかげんなやり方で解決したら
偶然としか思えないじゃない
ああ もう！
Darn it!
うん！
（ミリィ）セーフ
Safe!
（黒猫の鳴き声）
Still...
（メリル）でも…
Still, it is the unmistakable truth
that he solved each incident...
（メリル）
でも彼が 銃を使わずに—
事件を解決させたことは
紛れもない事実です
... without the use of his gun.
He refuses to harm anyone...
彼は 人を傷つけません
たとえ市民たちが—
... even citizens who try to kill him
for the bounty on his head.
賞金目当てに
命を狙ってきたとしても
There he is!! In here!
（市民）いたぞ ここだ！
（ヴァッシュ）マズッ
Oh, crap!
（女性Ａ）いたわ
（女性Ｂ）見ーつけた
- There he is!
- We found you!
フッ 僕のことかい？
Do you mean me?
（発砲音）
（ヴァッシュ）またかー
Get him!
Not again!!!
なぜ僕がこんな目に遭うの？ ママ
Why does this happen to me, Maman?
I haven't done anything wrong, but
everybody always picks on me, Maman!
何も悪いことしてないのに
みんなが僕をいじめるよ ママ
But now isn't the time
to be bawling in French.
…なーんて フランス語で
泣き入れてる場合じゃ
（メリル）
彼は なぜ このような行動を
取るのでしょうか？
Why does he act
the way he does?
I am able to surmise
part of the reason...
その理由は—
アイプリルシティにいる
モニカ･アレンさんの証言で—
... from the testimony of
Miss Monica Allen of Inepril City.
ある程度 推察できます
Your sacrifice
can save this city.
（モニカ･アレン）
あなた一人でこの町を救えるの？
So please let us catch you!
だからお願い 捕まって
Don't move!
動かないで！
I understand your situation well...
事情は とてもよく分かるよ
でも…
...but...
Please, don't move!!
お願い 動かないで！
（ヴァッシュ）
やつに会うまで 俺は—
Until I see him...
...I...
...have to keep moving!
立ち止まるわけにはいかないんだ
ハア ハア…
（ヴァッシュ）頼む
Please.
フワアーッ
Ma'am, who do you suppose
Mr. Vash meant by "him"?
先輩
“やつ”って
いったい誰なんでしょうね？
And so, he finally
took his gun into his hand.
（メリル）そして 彼は
ついに銃を握りました
He pulled the trigger
for the first time...
自分の命を狙っていた
人々を守るために—
... to save the very people
who had tried to kill him.
初めて引き金を引いたのです
（ネブラスカ）タイムリミット！
いっちょ脅したれ ゴフセフ
Time's up! Throw the fear
of death into him, Gofsef!
（ゴフセフ）だーっ！
（メリル）あっ！
（ゴフセフ）ブンッ
（サンディ）お母ちゃん！
Mommy!!
なんてことを！
How could you?!
アハハハハ…
えっ？
（どよめき）
Aw, you're doing just fine!
なんだ ピンピンしとるじゃないか
I was hoping you'd ditch the woman
and save your own skin!
いいとこ女をほっぽって
トンズラ決めると思ったがな
Mr. Vash isn't that
sort of a person!
ヴァッシュさんは
そんな人じゃないです！
はっ！
（ネブラスカ）ヘンッ
あくまでも殺さずってわけかよ
So you won't kill,
no matter what?
気持ち悪いやつ
You're disgusting!
However, that makes
you a hypocrite!
だがな
おめえのそれは偽善だ
え？
（ネブラスカ）絶対どこかで—
I know at some point you've killed
those who gave you a hard time.
不都合並べたやつを
消してきてんのさ
How do I know?
なぜなら 現におめえは
消される側に回ってねえ
Because you haven't yet
had your turn to be killed!
おめえに懸かっている
600億ダブドルの賞金が—
The $ $60,000,000,000 reward
on your head is proof!
何よりの証拠だ
ええ？ どうなんだよ！
What do you
say to that?!
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
Vash the Stampede!
ヘッ
え？
（ネブラスカ）
やっと その気になったようだな
So you're finally ready to fight!
おっ 抜くか？
Oh, you wanna draw?
You've felt it twice already!
Even your measly brain can realize...
２度もくらってんだ
息子のげんこつが
そんなもんじゃねえことぐらい—
...that my son's fist is
a force to be reckoned with!
てめえの うすら頭でも
分かるよな
This is your last chance to run!
Although, no matter how fast you run...
逃げるなら今のうちだぞ
もっとも
どんなに速く走ったところで—
...the next thing you know,
you'll be in tiny pieces!
気がついた次の瞬間
バラバラだがな
Now pay attention,
for I am about to lecture you...
いいか これから俺様が—
...on just how much of
a fool you really are!
お前が どれだけ愚かか
レクチャーしてやる
Using this!
こいつでな
My Human Mincemeat
Special Course!
人間ミンチのスペシャルコースだ！
（ヴァッシュ）うわっ
（ネブラスカ）早く助けに行け
Go help them, quick!
And then die in the
most humiliating way!
そして一番みっともない死にざまを
さらせや
（ゴフセフ）ドオン
（鼓動の音）
（銃声）
（ゴフセフ）ブオオーン！
うあああーっ
No way!
えっ ウソ
He changed its course!
（ヘンリー）そ… そらせた
That was great!
（トニス）すごーい
ガーッ…
He veered off my son's fist
with six bullets!
て… 鉄砲玉６発で
息子のげんこつ そらしやがった
Not quite.
違うな
I have one left.
It's a special one.
まだ１発残ってる
スペシャルなのがな
なあ…
（銃声）
（ゴフセフ）うおっ
うっ うう… ああーっ
What?!
（市民たちの悲鳴）
アハハ…
せ… 先輩
Ma'am, ma'am! He really beat him!!
I don't believe it!!
ホントにやっちゃいましたよ
あの人
And he did it with
only six bullets!
しかも たった６発の鉄砲玉だけで
Suddenly it's very clear to me...
（メリル）
今 はっきり分かったわ
あの人が—
...why he's called
The Humanoid Typhoon.
ヒューマノイド･タイフーンと
呼ばれるわけが
あの人が…
あの人が 本物の—
It's him...
He's the real...
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
...Vash the Stampede!
（メリル）
そうです　この人が—
"That's right!
This man IS..."
"...Vash the Stampede!"
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
なのです
（ヴァッシュ）ラブ＆ピース
（メリル）え？
Love & peace!
（ヴァッシュ）
ラブ＆ピース　ラブ＆ピース
ラブ＆ピース
LOVE & PEACE.
うわあああーっ！
You're fun to watch, ma'am.
（ミリィ）
先輩って面白いですねえ
ふああー
（黒猫の鳴き声）
（ミリィの寝言）
...mille-feuille...
（メリル）
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
Vash the Stampede...
私は 彼の行動を
見続けるたびに—
Every time I
observe his actions...
... I am unable to help but sense
there is something hidden within him...
その中に潜む何かを
感じずにはいられませんでした
... a thing we can't
hope to understand.
私たちには理解できない 何かを
ですが これだけは言えます
But this much is certain:
Everyone who has
become involved with him...
彼に関わった人たちは皆
失った思いを取り戻していると…
... has regained an emotion
which was once lost to them.
（ステファニー）パパ！
Daddy!
パパ… パパ！
Daddy, Daddy!
It's only my shoulder.
（ボストーク伯爵）
肩を撃たれただけだ
（エリザベス）ああ…
こんなことって…
This can't be...
It was you?
あなただなんて…
（Ｂ.Ｄ.ネオン）
いつも言ってんだろ
It's like I always say.
Nothing shines
like hard-won fame.
命張るから
看板ってのは光るのよ
（カイト）あっ…
ああ！
（ジュリアス）
僕たちだけの力で生きていきます
From now on, we'll live
without relying on anyone.
Except for each other.
（ジュリアス）二人だけの力で
（ムーア）フフッ
I'm not amazing.
すごくなんかないよ
（メリル）なのに…
Despite that...
あっ！ ヴァッシュさん
Mr. Vash!
STAY BACK!
（ヴァッシュ）来るな！
Stay away from me.
来ちゃダメだ
That's not him...
That's not the man I know...
違う…
私の知ってるあの人とは違う
Who is that?
あの人は誰？
Is that the real
Vash the Stampede?
あれがホントの
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード？
The evil $ $60,000,000,000 outlaw
with Hell's Fire burning in his eyes?
悪魔にみいられ 瞳に炎を宿した
600億ダブドルの賞金首
（銃声）
（モネヴ･ザ･ゲイル）
うわー！ ぐはっ…
You'll pay...
You'll pay for this!
許さねえ
許さねえぞ！
（足音）
（モネヴ）おおっ
People are dead.
（ヴァッシュ）
人が死んだ　死んでしまった
They're dead.
So what?!
だから どうした？
うわあ
うわっ　ああっ
People are dead!
人が死んだ
THEY'RE DEAD!
死んだんだ！
（モネヴ）ううう…
You killed them!
お前が殺したんだ
ひえええ
You die with them!!
お前も死ね！
（メリル）ハッ！
ハア…
（メリル）
どっちが本当のあの人なの？
Which is the real man?
I don't understand!
私には… 分からない
You understand, don't you? We're all
scared! We can't sleep at night!
（男）
分かるだろ みんな不安なんだよ
夜も眠れないんだ
You're not the only one.
（宿屋主人）
うちこそ なんとかしたいんだ
誰か言ってくれないかね？
Can't someone tell him
to get out of this hotel?
この宿から出て行けってさ
Tell Vash the Stampede to
get out? Are you insane?!
（男）
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードにか？
おい… 冗談だろ
（大きな物音）
（メリル）あっ
（ヴァッシュ）
あちゃー！ 何じゃー
OW!
（ミリィ）ああ あ…
（メリル）何があったんですの？
ヴァッシュさん
What happened, Mr. Vash?
（メリルとミリィ）あ…
（メリル）ああ…
うーん イヤん
Eek!
（メリルとミリィ）ああっ
（メリル）
その傷が 相手を殺すことなく
ねじ伏せてきた—
So those scars
are the price you paid...
...for dealing with your opponents
without killing them?
代償というわけですわね
（ヴァッシュ）
女の子には あんまり
見せたくなかったんだけどね
It's not something I
really want girls to see.
They'd run away.
モテなくなっちゃうから
そんなこと…
No, they...
そんなことありませんわ
No, they wouldn't.
ヴァッシュさん いったい
何が起こっているんですか？
Mr. Vash, what is going on?
あなたは何もしていないのに
騒ぎが降りかかって—
You haven't done anything, yet
these things keep happening to you...
町の人には
白い目で見られるし—
...the townspeople look
at you with contempt...
Doesn't that bother you?
悔しくないんですの？
やめにしませんか？
そんな生き方
Won't you stop
living the way you do?
（ヴァッシュ）ダメだ
I can't.
ダメなんだよ
I can't do that.
俺は過去を清算していない
I haven't buried my past.
それを知っているのに
安穏と生きていくなんて—
How can I live in peace
with that hanging over me?
許されるはずないじゃないか
（保安官）行くのか？
Are you leaving?
すんません 見逃してもらって
Thanks for letting
me go like this.
この町に
いてもらいたくねえだけだ
I don't want you in
my city, that's all.
Don't thank me...
礼なんて言うより
早くここから消えてくれ
...just leave.
ハハッ そうですね
You're right.
やっぱり ついていくんですね
So you are following him?
Of course. It's my job.
もちろん　お仕事ですもの
I see!
そうですか
Very well! I can't leave you two
alone together, so I shall come along!
じゃあ私は 二人とも
ほうっておけないので—
ご一緒します
Argh! You're both frank
and devious, Milly!
もうっ
素直かつ狡猾(こうかつ)ですわね ミリィ
（ヴァッシュ）おお！ お嬢さん
砂漠の一人旅は危険が危ないですよ
Young lady! Travelling alone
in the desert can be very perilous!
If you act now, you can hire
your own bodyguard, free of charge...
今なら無料で
ボディーガードが雇えるんですけど
...what do you say?
いかがでしょうか？
もう！ ちょっと目を離すと
すぐこれなんだから
Honestly! I only take
my eyes off him for an instant!
がーっ ちょっと待って！
無視しないでくださいよ
Wait! Don't walk away!
Young lady! Young lady?
お嬢さん お嬢さん…
Vash the Stampede, hm?
（メリル）
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード… か
ヘヘッ
♪〜
〜♪
（ヴァッシュ）前を向いていると
見落としてしまうことがある
If you keep facing forward,
you can miss seeing something.
自分の考えを固く信じ—
It is a virtue to devote oneself,
firmly believing one's own ideals.
ただひたすらに走り続けるのは
美徳だ
But that doesn't mean you may belittle
the ideals or feelings of others.
だが 他人の気持ちや思いを
ないがしろにして いいわけがない
Even if you lead such a busy life, you
never realize how your parents feel.
父と母の思いに気づかないまま
がむしゃらに生きたとしても—
That is only self-satisfaction.
自己満足でしかない
時には立ち止まるのもいい
It's all right to stop
every now and again.
If you want
a moment's rest.
しばしの休息であるのなら
If you want to feel
what other people feel.
人の思いが感じられるのなら